<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Monkeyology</title>
    <description>A girly environmental science blog</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/homepage/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/homepage/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Mon, 15 May 2023 21:39:32 -0700</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 May 2023 21:39:32 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.9.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>My Experiences with Feminism</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Ammonium thioglycolate can do amazing things – it lets people take their 1A pin-straight hair to 2C curls after a single trip to the salon, helps girls &lt;em&gt;everywhere&lt;/em&gt; find stylish hair to match their bone structure, and was a key piece of logic in Elle Woods’s case in the movie Legally Blonde. I already have curly hair, though. Why should I care?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s why: when I watched Elle Woods solve the biggest celebrity murder case of the year, emphasizing ammonium thioglycolate’s effects in a loud, booming voice with even louder Prada heels, something shifted in me. (There was an even more permanent change than, say, the one brought upon by an ammonium thioglycolate-assisted perm.) For the first time ever, Elle Woods showed me a representation of femininity and logic combined into one. Shortly after the first rewatch, I started coming to school with Elle Woods-type regalia, red dresses, fancy shoes, bold nails, and a red lip. Hoodies became blouses, messy hair became beachy waves, and I became myself again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You see, in a small STEM school, it seems that fitting in is crucial to be respected: if you’re not blending in, how can you be expected to solve a math problem as quickly as everyone else?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By dressing in feminine outfits, you are often seen as dumber than everyone else. Your ideas are ignored, your questions spark laughter and gossip, and preconceptions about your intelligence seem to rest solely on whether you wear a dress one day or a hoodie the other. It starts to become a choice. Which one, approval or authenticity?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Elle Woods picked authenticity. When she saw how her classmates responded to her feminity, she chose to look within herself, studying harder than ever before. She kept an open law textbook perched on her elliptical, used law arguments to get her nail tech her stolen dog back, and, ultimately, created her own law: &lt;em&gt;Make it happen. Shock everyone.&lt;/em&gt; That’s the thing. For so many people, femininity will always be seen as inferior and paired with a lack of analytical ability and problem-solving skills. It is therefore up to women to take control of their identity by choosing authenticity over the approval of others, although they will face backlash in fields like STEM or law.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I walk into a room now, I acknowledge that any ideas I bring to the table – about environmental science, environmental policy, whatever it may be – are not undermined by whether my makeup is too heavy or not.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 08 May 2023 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/homepage/steminism/2023/05/08/my-experiences-with-feminism.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/homepage/steminism/2023/05/08/my-experiences-with-feminism.html</guid>
        
        <category>Feminism</category>
        
        <category>You Can Help</category>
        
        
        <category>STEMinism</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Driving Force Behind Environmental Science</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;With all the topics I have learned in environmental science, there is one concept that unites them all. It explains why people make the environmental choices they do; even more than that, it explains how animals like monkeys interact with each other, why I study for hours some days and others I listen to music and daydream instead, and where the motives behind the rapper Logic’s songs originate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You see, these topics are all linked by the intrinsic battle of greed and compassion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s what drives monkeys to make the decisions they make: monkeys are greedy. They steal bananas from their friends, they block other monkeys from going in the shade so they can have all of it, they cause a lot of pain to other animals for food. But they’re also compassionate – that’s why they take care of their families, they hunt for their group, they protect the weaker monkeys.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s the reason I have days when I don’t study even though I think I should. I would rather be greedy, stealing the time I allotted and using it as a currency to spend on other things, than be compassionate to myself by prioritizing the girl who wants an amazing future. Greed and compassion alone are each addicting. Should you get addicted to both?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On those days when I don’t study, I listen to Logic instead. In “Come on Down,” he raps about Daquan from Southeast D.C. In the song, Daquan tells the Houdini of the music industry, “I want the world, I want the money, I want the respect.” On the first listen, you imagine a 35-year-old Daquan after three studio albums, two Grammys, and one failed marriage drowning in his gold and riches out of the greed that comes from fame and attention. Then, you realize on the second listen that Daquan from the future could look very different: he could sell his soul to the music industry, using all the profits to make a better life for himself and his family while spreading important messages to millions of people. It all depends on perspective.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Think about all these situations. They are analogous to how people act, who will externalize costs to the environment or to the health of others so they can make more money, but who have also formed advocacy groups to protect other people and organisms. The controversies in environmental science and policy would not exist without the discourse between these separate groups. They exist because people have to fight between greed and compassion for every choice that we make.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 27 Apr 2023 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/homepage/nikki's%20takedown/2023/04/27/the-driving-force-behind-environmental-science.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/homepage/nikki's%20takedown/2023/04/27/the-driving-force-behind-environmental-science.html</guid>
        
        <category>Opinion</category>
        
        
        <category>Nikki&apos;s takedown</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Blog Introduction</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;All you need to know as the premise to this blog is that I am listening to SZA right now while writing this. The point of this blog is to show you diverse perspectives and novel things going on in the world of environmental science – the “monkey’s world,” if it’s not too soon – and have a little bit of fun while doing so. The blog is split into five sections: Book Reviews; Nikki’s Takedown; Podcast, Summarized; STEMinism; and Advice Column.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Book Reviews&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here, you can find in-depth reviews for a ton of books. They aren’t just about environmental science – some of them touch on the topic briefly but were ultimately written with similar core values and motives in mind as environmental science books. 
For example, one article in this section reviews “The Life You Can Save,” which presents common arguments for not giving and breaks them down logically as well as discusses the best ways for Americans to donate and help those who are living in poverty. I included it in this blog because it has a similar goal as some environmental science books, which is to help people combat the abuse and degradation inflicted upon others when they are in a state to do so. 
Other books talk about environmental science, but they are not just your run-of-the-mill-conserving-biodiversity reads. See, I’m a girl with &lt;strong&gt;very specific taste.&lt;/strong&gt; If I like a book, it has fresh new takes . . . and all of said takes will be chewed up and regurgitated in this Book Reviews section.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nikki’s Takedown&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is my favorite section because I LOVE the sound of my own voice. Nikki’s Takedown serves a dual purpose – it acts both to share my opinion on how and where specific environmental issues can be addressed and as an opinion column about things that have been going on in the environmental world. 
While reading, you’ll find yourself asking, &lt;em&gt;Uruguay did that HOW?&lt;/em&gt; at the cultural shift Uruguay created to make clean energy a major part of its national practices and exclaiming, &lt;em&gt;¡No me digas!”&lt;/em&gt; at the causes of the Puerto Rican energy crisis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Podcast, Summarized&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Did you guys know there’s a podcast that goes along with this blog? It’s called “Monkeyology” too, and you can find it wherever you get your podcasts.
Podcast, Summarized is a section for all the reading aficionados who don’t like to listen to the podcast episodes or want a more succinct version.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;STEMinism&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I bet you noticed the pink that covers basically every inch of this blog. You see, one of the things I continue to keep in mind while working on this project  is that it is my responsibility to stress that authenticity and expression are important pillars of everyone’s identity, including mine. In the past, dressing authentically to myself – in a feminine way – has been frowned upon and judged, but despite this negative shared experience among women in STEM, it is important to keep presenting how you want to, because you were meant to stand out! Femininity does not take away from intelligence and analytical ability.
That’s why this section will be a shameless commentary on things like Legally Blonde’s influence on feminism, the best makeup for the environment, and sustainable fashion tips. Keep being you!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Advice Column&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You know those advice columns written in response to people nicknamed “worried girlfriend” and “boy with the blues?” This is basically that, but the environmental version. Send your questions to amonkeysworld@gmail.com or to monkeyology on Instagram. Letters from “concerned composter,” “biodiversity bro,” “precautionary polluter,” and the like will be greatly appreciated.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 27 Apr 2023 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/homepage/blog/2023/04/27/blog-introduction.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/homepage/blog/2023/04/27/blog-introduction.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>Blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
